Tyler J. Roberts

(262) 388-4050 | tjroberts314@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyleroberts | https://github.com/tyler314

Summary

Software engineer with 6+ years experience in development and design. My most recent work has been well-balanced between building back-end systems, and front-end web applications. I'm seeking a role where I can leverage the experience I have to be a contributing member to a passionate team, that also requires me to learn new skill sets to succeed.

Experience

Software Engineer & Project Manager

Copper + Honey Salon \cdot Freelance

Feb 2023 - Present · Remote

- https://www.copperandhoneysalon.com
- Delivered fully functional website from scratch, leveraging AWS tools to quickly launch in time for the client's grand opening.
- Leveraged SEO techniques to optimize Google indexing, resulting in the website to be in the top results for hair extensions in the local area. Consistently getting 300+ clicks every month.
- Designed solution for the client so they can easily add and remove employees from the site, seamlessly working across all screen sizes. Giving my clients the autonomy to edit their employee page on their own, at any point.
- I work directly with the owners and an independent UX Designer, in order to design software solutions, create timelines, and conduct demos to deliver the best product for my clients' needs.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Javascript, React.js, Material UI, SEO.

Software Engineer

Warner Bros. Discovery · Contract

 $Mar 2023 - Dec 2023 \cdot Remote$

- Within my first month I became a key team contributor by quickly becoming a part of on-call rotations, contributing to code reviews, and pushing code, allowing our team to meet the MAX launch deadline in May.
- Led efforts of designing novel integration tests, and setting up new Grafana monitoring + alerts for the team's new MAX services. Required research, cross-team collaboration and team sign-offs resulting in our new services meeting company SLA requirements.
- I became the lead engineer tasked with onboarding a new service from a re-org. Required collaboration with three away teams, to understand it and get the service running before my contract's end.
- General Operational Excellence. Served on-call shifts, performed load tests before big launches, contributed to documentation for the new services we were building.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, Kafka, Grafana, Kubernetes + Docker

Software Engineer

Amazon.com · Full-Time

Dec 2019 - Jan 2023 · Seattle, WA

- Lead engineer delivering adapted responses for Smart Home requests. Features such as sharing customer insights, listing device capabilities, and having Alexa say "Good Morning / Night" when toggling a smart light.
- Developed Brief / Verbose Mode for ACMS. Allowed the authoring of responses targeted to customers who have their devices' setting turned on, or turned off. Designed the data format for the front-end, working with internal 3P teams to onboard them to this new service, and developed filtering logic to serve personalized responses based on the individual customer.
- Migrated all Alexa personality content from a legacy CMS, to ACMS/ARMS. A three month endeavor that required the development of bulk migration scripts, working closely with a select few engineers, PMs, and content creators across all supported locales. Had daily standups just for this project.
- Led the org in hiring engineers by conducting over 50 interviews in Q1 2022. Allowed the org to get a higher head count for hiring. Received the quarterly award for this effort.
- Social chair for the org, responsible for organizing quarterly events encouraging teammates to socialize outside of work. I felt this was especially important during the post-pandemic world where many teammates didn't see each other as often due to remote work.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Kotlin, Javascript, React.js, CI/CD Code Pipelines, Git

Software Engineer

Cockroach Labs · Full-Time

May 2019 − Sep 2019 · New York, NY

Cockroach Labs

- Apart of the Bulk I/O team, which is responsible for bulk operations in the database, including backup and restore, and schema changes in the database.
- Fixed issue where the dump operation would include interleaved table statements inside of create table statements, causing dependency issues upon a restore.
- Designed features for the backup & restore process to include additional metadata about the cluster. Required a redesign of how the process worked, and reduced manual steps by the user.
- Tools & Technologies: Golang, SQL, Git/Github.

Software Engineer

Dataminr · Full-Time

Sep 2018 - Feb 2019 · New York, NY

- Work on developing the tools used to search and filter through the Twitter pipeline and other media sources.
- JVM code base comprised of Scala and Java. Applications ran on AWS, and much of the day to day work involved use with the AWS tech stack. Kinesis was used for processing the large data sources, where S3 was used to store the raw data.
- Migrated Pastebin data source from Kinesis to Kafka. Involved dependencies between several teams, and required collaboration amongst them.
- Tools & Technologies: Scala, Java, Maven, Docker, AWS, Google Guice, Git/Gitlab, IntelliJ, MacOS.

Software Engineer

IBM Corporation · Full-Time

Jul 2017 - Aug 2019 · Yorktown Heights, NY

- Developed Python application on another team that moved their locally stored data and user accounts to Bluemix, IBM's cloud platform as a service.
- Designed and engineered a web application from the ground up using HTML, CSS, Angular, and Bootstrap. Responsible for the front-end, including page navigation using an MVC design pattern.
- Used Docker to rigorously test the deployment of the web application onto the servers.
- Tools & Technologies: Python, Docker, HTML, Angular, Javascript, PyCharm, MacOS.

Education

B.S. Computer Engineering, Computer Science, & Mathematics with Physics Certificate (minor). University of Wisconsin - Madison, May 2017